hey everybody welcome to this a2 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and become a member at
patreon.com listeningtime so you can
receive my listening practice seminars
sound training videos and bonus podcast
episodes okay today we're going to talk
about communication
this is an extremely important topic
because all of us need to communicate in
our daily lives first of all let's talk
about some of the different ways that
people communicate in the past
communication was pretty simple you
could talk to people in person you could
call people on the phone or you could
write people a letter but nowadays there
are lots of other ways for people to
communicate with each other the internet
has given us many more methods of
communication nowadays for most young
people sending messages is more common
than actually talking to people they use
messaging apps social media apps and
normal text messaging we also have video
call platforms like skype and zoom this
technology has completely changed the
way that we communicate however there
are some things related to communication
that will always be the same for example
communication always requires effort you
need to make an effort to call someone
send them a message or knock on their
door communicating with others takes
effort energy and time another thing
that's necessary for good communication
is good listening skills do you know
someone that isn't a good listener this
person probably isn't a fun person to
talk to when someone only talks about
themselves and they don't ask you
questions this can be annoying or boring
when you talk to someone who really
listens to you it's much more satisfying
so this is something that we can all
practice with being better listeners
another important part of communication
is having empathy empathy is the ability
to understand and feel what other people
are feeling when you talk to someone
who's empathetic it feels like they
understand you and they care about you
but when you talk to someone who's not
empathetic you probably don't feel this
way one other skill that can help your
communication is humor this refers to
being funny when people have a good
sense of humor it's really fun to talk
to them because you can laugh together
humor makes communication more
interesting in general okay now let's
talk about some of the difficulties with
communication one of the hardest
situations is when you're talking to
someone who speaks a different language
i'm sure many of you have had the
opportunity to speak english to someone
who doesn't speak your language this is
both exciting and hard it's exciting
because you get to practice your english
in a real situation but it's hard
because english isn't your native
language you can't express yourself how
you express yourself in your language of
course this is why you're learning
english so that you can speak to people
from other countries more effectively
another thing that can be difficult is
if you're a shy person people who are
shy usually don't feel comfortable
meeting new people and talking to many
people i used to be shy when i was a kid
but i think people can become less shy
if they practice if you force yourself
to speak to people often it'll start to
become more normal for you you'll feel a
little less uncomfortable after a while
one last difficulty that people have is
public speaking most people don't like
speaking in front of a large audience it
doesn't feel good when everyone is
watching you if you have to give a
presentation to an audience the best
thing you can do is really prepare and
memorize your presentation beforehand if
you do this you'll be able to say what
you need to say even if you're nervous
okay that's all for today remember to
download the listening time podcast and
become a member at
patreon.comlisteningtime to receive my
listening practice seminars my sound
training videos and extra podcast
episodes also subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram i'll see you next time
[Music]
you